

Proactive software developer with more than 10 years of experience in iOS Apps development. I have implemented valuable features that leads to MAU growth in several worldwide apps like Viber, Yandex Browser, etc. I have contributed to successful startups based in USA

Kanstantsin Bucha

Phone: +48 509 001 795

E-mail: kanstantsin.bucha@icloud.com

- I have been leading a team of 10 people for 1 year
- I have been developing on iOS for 10 years, MacOS for 2 years.
- I have been managing mobile team (both iOS and Android)
- I have strong background working with logs and fixing issues remotely.
- I developed all software of the multiplatform startup from the ground.
- I get used to best practices of Agile development with release trains, TDD, CI running unit test, documentation in Jira, Confluence.
- I mastered a git workflow long time ago.

Languages

English – C1 Russian – C2 Polish – A1

Programming Languages:
Swift, ObjC, C, C++, Kotlin,
Type Script
Cl
Azure, Jenkins etc
Git repo:
Bitbucket, Github, GitLab etc
Project management:
Jira, Asana, Monday

Process.

Experience

Lead IOS Software Developer and Group Manager

Coherent Solutions Poland, September 2020 - Present

IOS Software Developer

RakutenViber *Minsk,Bealrus* September 2018 – September 2020

Freelance on USA market Lida, Belarus October 2014 - September 2018

R-Style Lab *Minsk, Belarus* October 2013 - October 2014

EPAM Systems *Minsk, Belarus* April 2012 - October 2013

Education

2006 - 2012

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Bachelor

Achievements

As part of Viber team I implemented features that Viber users like a lot, that leads to MAU growth

* My Notes (close to 70% users using it on daily basis), **Disappearing** Messages (secure conversations became more convenient)

As part of Coherent Solutions team I participated in development of cross platform secure transport protocol design, and guided It implementation for iOS and MacOS clients. That allowed password less solution product of the customer got next seeding round as an innovation tech based startup.

My pet project is an iot air pollution detecting device that we developed with friends. It now going to reach the pre-seed funding stage. My part was the software programming for ESP32, mobile iOS and Android apps, Server side written in Type Script and developing the device schematic.

Coherent Solutions Poland, September 2020 - Present

Project under NDA - Password less access to all company resources B2B

- CI on Azure, Jira/Confluence, Monday, Bitbucket, Slack, TestFlight, Scrum
- Ble, Sockets, Stomp, Pushes, Silent Pushes, GoogleAnalytics, Crashlytics, Core Data
- VIPER, TDD, Swift, Swift Package Manager, Cocoapods, Storyboards, bundled as Framework

RakutenViber Minsk, Bealrus September 2018 – September 2020

Project Viber on iOS – mobile messaging app MAU 180 000 000

- CI Jenkins, Jira/Confluence, Git Lab, Viber, TestFlight, Feature Driven Development
- Pushes, Silent Pushes, iOS Extensions, Camera, Sound, Core Data
- AdMob, MoPub, MyTarget, Yandex SKAdNetwork, GDPR, IAB Europe
- VIPER, UnitTests, ObjC+Swift, C++, Xibs, bundled as Umbrella Framework

Freelance on USA market Lida, Belarus October 2015 - December 2018

QromaScan, QromaTag on iOS, QromaTag MacOS – Scan photos and slides to cloud, tag by speaking

- No CI, Asana, Bitbucket, Testflight, Agile
- Camera, Core Image, Shaders. Speech Recognition, Linguistic parsing, iCloud, DropBox, Core Data
- MVVM, ObjC, Storyboards, Cocoapods, bundled as Cocoapod

Project under NDA – Social networking app for students

- No CI, Asana, Bitbucket, Testflight, Agile
- Camera, Integration with Universities API, Google Firebase, Core Data
- MVVM, ObjC, Storyboards, Cocoapods, bundled as Cocoapod

Barefoot Solutions (as remote developer) – Vizispect – App for Home Inspectors

- No CI, Asana, Bitbucket, Testflight, Agile
- Camera, PDF generation and Cloud printing services, Core Data, Maps, Navigation
- View Interactor Presenter, ObjC, Storyboards, Cocoapods, bundled as Cocoapod

R-Style Lab Minsk, Belarus October 2013 - October 2014

Several Projects under NDA

- CI Jenkins, Jira/Asana, Git Lab, E-Mail, TestFlight, Agile
- Pushes, Silent Pushes, Camera, Sound, Core Data, Maps, Navigation
- MVC/MVP, ObjC, Xibs, no bundles, Pixel Perfect implementation

EPAM Systems Minsk, Belarus April 2012 - October 2013

Yandex Maps, Yandex Browser, MAU – 9 000 000 (on 2012)

- CI Jenkins, Jira, Git Lab, E-Mail, TestFlight, Waterfall
- Pushes, Silent Pushes, Camera, Sound, Core Data
- MVC, UnitTests, ObjC, C++, Xibs, no bundles